<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
<title><![CDATA[Peter's Blog]]></title>
<description><![CDATA[Peter's Blog]]></description>
<link>https://peterjauhal.github.io/</link>
<lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2023 13:23:34 +0000</lastBuildDate>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[Death]]></title>
  <description><![CDATA[
<p>
Throughout my life I have been close to suicide several times - especially when I was 18 years old and feeling totally isolated. My life since the age of 18 has been pretty good and, especially after age 48, my life hhas been very enjoyable.
</p>

<p>
However if I died today, I would consider it a great blessing. I find it is a huge burden to keep my brain entertained and my body fit and healthy.
</p>

<p>
Dealing with the world gives me no pleasure and I have no interest in seeing the future of humanity. In fact, being a human being is a form of suffering even when we are not in physical pain. I, as well as most humans, have been betrayed, abandoned and rejected by people several times in my life - even by my parents and sister!! So living in this world is a hellish experience even when you are physically well.
</p>

<p>
So the question is: why not commit suicide? The answer is that I believe in reincarnation and so if you do commit suicide you will only have to return and complete the tour again in the future. You have to go through the tests in this world and use them to make yourself strong. As Doestoevsky says - the stars shine brightest in the darkest night. So really the human world is a quality control process to weed out the people who can survive and thrive in it without it letting them get it down. When we reach a high level of development, we should be able to experience ecstasy just in ordinary human experiences.
</p>

<p>
I am not at that level. My spritual practice does let me experience intense happiness but this is not yet consistent thoughout the day. From another point of view my spiritual practice is a form of suicide or preparation for death. And so there is no incosistency in enjoying a spiritual practice and looking forward to death - maybe that is why I enjoy my spiritual practice so much.
</p>
<div class="taglist"><a href="https://peterjauhal.github.io/tags.html">Tags</a>: <a href="https://peterjauhal.github.io/tag-spirituality.html">spirituality</a> </div>]]></description>
  <category><![CDATA[spirituality]]></category>
  <link>https://peterjauhal.github.io/2023-12-15-death.html</link>
  <guid>https://peterjauhal.github.io/2023-12-15-death.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2023 19:36:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[Can spirituality be fun?]]></title>
  <description><![CDATA[
<p>
I am 61 years old and in my life I have experienced deeply several major religions - Sikhism, Chritianity and Chinee Buddhism. I have also read about most ooher spiriual practices. At the moment I am training to be a Tibetan Buddhist lama over a 3 year course and I have for the first time realised that spirituality is fun!!
</p>

<p>
All of my life, the priests have come across as being serious and miserable with sermons that admonish us in one way or other. The people in the temples and churches are quiet and deadly serious. But surely this is wrong - does not God want us to enjoy his creation? Why would he want us to be miserable and sad?
</p>

<p>
My Tibetan Buddhist lama is always laughing and smiling and making jokes. He is 70 years old but he still has the vivaciousess of a small boy. He is quite clear in his teaching: if you are not having fun and enjoying the practices, then you should not carry on training with him.
</p>

<p>
So far, as well as Tibetan Buddhist philosophy, he has taught us hundreds of meditatons. Each meditation has its own visualisations, mantras and hand mudras. My teacher says that each person is different and so they need to choose the meditations to practice that work best for them. This means that the course is never boring and my mind and body is going through continuos changes which are very surprising to me.
</p>

<p>
He says that we are effectively preparing for our deaths and that we will go through several deaths and rebirths as we continue to practice. My mood has been consistently good during the course and so I will let you know when or if I go through <b><b>a dark night of thr soul</b></b>.
</p>
<div class="taglist"><a href="https://peterjauhal.github.io/tags.html">Tags</a>: <a href="https://peterjauhal.github.io/tag-spirtuality,.html">spirtuality,</a> <a href="https://peterjauhal.github.io/tag-tibetan.html">Tibetan</a> <a href="https://peterjauhal.github.io/tag-buddhism.html">Buddhism</a> </div>]]></description>
  <category><![CDATA[spirtuality,]]></category>
  <category><![CDATA[Tibetan]]></category>
  <category><![CDATA[Buddhism]]></category>
  <link>https://peterjauhal.github.io/2023-12-15-can-spirituality-be-fun?.html</link>
  <guid>https://peterjauhal.github.io/2023-12-15-can-spirituality-be-fun?.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2023 19:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[Why am I writing this blog?]]></title>
  <description><![CDATA[
<p>
Welcome to this blog! The question that I ask myself is why am I starting this blog? Does this question need an answer? Does everything we do have to hve a purpose so that we are efficient in some way? I think not. Human beings are not machines or assets that need to be made more and more efficient. We can do things which are not logical. In fact the Italian philosopher Wilfriedo Pareto actually thinks that most human actions are not based on reason.
</p>

<p>
Given this I can still provide some reasons:
</p>
<ul class="org-ul">
<li>I want my future self to be able to read what I was thinking at this stage in my life. So one of the rules I will follow is not to change a blog entry once I have posted.</li>
<li>I want to do something creative in my life. I consume a vast amount of information every day and it would be good to see how my brain has assimilated all of the information that I have consumed.</li>
<li>I have written a book and many poems but nowhere have I attempted to write my understanding of life.</li>
</ul>

<p>
I am not writing this blog to become popular or to have a following. It is purely for my personal use and for monitoring my self-development over the years. Of course, there are risks involved with sharing my thoughts. It is possible that some of my views may not be acceptable to the British Government now or at some point in the future and I may be arrested for expressing these views on this blog. I think this is unlikely but if it does occur I will treat this as part of my spiritual cultivation.
</p>

<p>
I do not know hwow frequently I will write - it maybe every day or once a month. We will see.
</p>

<p>
So let's start this journey into the unknown together!!
</p>
<div class="taglist"><a href="https://peterjauhal.github.io/tags.html">Tags</a>: <a href="https://peterjauhal.github.io/tag-goals.html">goals</a> </div>]]></description>
  <category><![CDATA[goals]]></category>
  <link>https://peterjauhal.github.io/2023-12-15-why-am-i-writing-this-blog?.html</link>
  <guid>https://peterjauhal.github.io/2023-12-15-why-am-i-writing-this-blog?.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2023 19:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title><![CDATA[A beautiful picture]]></title>
  <description><![CDATA[
<p>
I am training to be a Tibetan lama and so I think this is an appropriate picture to start the blog with.
</p>


<figure id="orgd032608">
<img src="./pictures/F5PGVBsaMAAYPK6.jpeg" alt="F5PGVBsaMAAYPK6.jpeg">

</figure>
<div class="taglist"><a href="https://peterjauhal.github.io/tags.html">Tags</a>: <a href="https://peterjauhal.github.io/tag-spirituality.html">spirituality</a> </div>]]></description>
  <category><![CDATA[spirituality]]></category>
  <link>https://peterjauhal.github.io/2023-12-14-test-with-image.html</link>
  <guid>https://peterjauhal.github.io/2023-12-14-test-with-image.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2023 13:27:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
